

DEREK GROVE Full-Stack Developer

Consulting Engineer for MongoDB, Inc. I have 7 years of experience with a strong back-ground within all layers of application development, notably MERN and Oracle/J2EE stacks. I strive to be minimalistic and you'll find me in the great outdoors or in the garage turning wrenches if I'm not behind a desk.

Contact

- 7753 Skyline Dr. Harrisburg PA, 17112
- (412) 500 3600
- derekjgrove@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/derekjgrove

- Multiple Deloitte cash Applause Awards
- 2nd place PNC API Fest 2.2 Hackathon
- PHEAA Ready to Succeed Scholarship Recipient



Professional Experience

MongoDB, Inc.

Feb 2022 - Present

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES: CONSULTING ENGINEER

Work with multiple client engagements

- · Work directly with clients' stakeholders, architects, team leads, and other personnel
- · Provide expertise for many different roles and architectures
- Troubleshoot and perform RCA for degraded environments
- · Conduct performance evaluations
- Offer solutions or best practices for a given scenario
- · Create PoCs for specific feature compatibility
- Perform code reviews in any language, focusing on correct data access patterns
- Plan migration strategies
- · Model data based on noSQL schema designs
- Create internal tools to help the PS organization

Deloitte Consulting LLP. MERN FULL-STACK TEAM LEAD

Jan 2020 - Feb 2022

GAAP Checklist - Global and external Audit tool built as a SPA that has realtime collaboration.

https://checklist.disclosureanalytics.deloitte.com



- · Perform code reviews and complete merge requests
- Conduct sprint planning with Stake-holders and run daily scrum calls
- Close any Production incidents and meet with external user[s] in case of triage
- Run and plan deployments and disaster recovery tests
- Increase security by working with Pen-testers and Fority scans
- Use AzureAD token Validation when applications call our services
- Improve performance by getting Performance Engineering team feedback and making services optimizations, React.js built-in utilities usage, memory and event-handler management
- Scale application with .NET Core Webjobs and Azure ServiceBus
- · Re-design Real-time engine with Socket.io and Redis
- Introduce Singleton design pattern on top of the Factory design pattern
- Stabilize back-end by adding layered architecture
- · Upgrade Webpack, Babel and other build tools to allow chunking and other compression benefits
- Add AzureAD through OIDC as a way to authenticate
- Decomission legacy tool and work with F5 team for redirect and internal only access managed by Azure AD groups
- Lead the UI over-haul, making all of the UI Omnia compliant and more modular

Deloitte Consulting LLP. MERN FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

GAAP Checklist

- · Develop back-end processes using Node.js and Express.js
- Implement secure APIs using JWT bearer tokens and make rest calls with NTLM authentication
- Develop web pages with React is and stylus
- · Create Unit tests with Mocha and Chai libraries
- Abide by best application data designs and abide by OOP with ES6
- Implement real-time synchronization with ShareDB and racer-highway
- Provide data adjustments and other various DB reports
- Determine best DB schema designs and other Data-Architect tasks
- Help manage Kubernetes Pods in Non-Production environments
- Migrate to Azure web services from previous On-Premise Kubernetes environment

PNC Financial Services Group, Inc.

Aug 2015 - Sept 2017

RISK APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Data adjustment application built on a Java/Oracle stack. Various reports built by a BI tool were sent to regulatory agencies.

- Create pages with Struts framework action classes and JQuery
- Develop POJOs, DAOs, and services with Java Spring framework
- Develop Regulatory and Finance reports sent to the Federal Bank with AxiomSL alongside BSAs
- Lead and developed automatic NDM file transfer protocol of the 2052a report to the Federal Bank with Shell and Oracle Wallet
- Troubleshoot issues that occur in Oracle DB with OEM and IBM WAS
- Managed Java Application deployments to IBM WAS with Jenkins and IBM uDeploy

()

Technical Skills





Education

Indiana University of Pennsylvania BACHELOR OF SCIENCES

Aug 2011 - May 2015

BACHELUR OF SCIENCES

Major: Computer Science Magna Cum Laude Graduate